Guide to Cyrus Mason Correspondence MC.30
New York University Archives
Cyrus Mason Letters
1843
New York University Archives
Mason, Cyrus, 1798-1865
MC.30
0.25 Linear Feet in one half manuscript box
This collection contains the personal correspondence of Cyrus Mason, 1798-1865. The letters mainly cover personal matters such as religion, the birth of a daughter, and finances.
Biography of Cyrus Mason
Born July 19, 1798, near Nassau, New York, Cyrus Mason served as the pastor of the Cedar Street Presbyterian Church in New York City (forerunner of the Fifth Avenue Presbyterian Church). Mason was a member of the original Council of New York University (NYU), then called the University of the City of New York. In 1836 Mason became Professor of the Evidences of Revealed Religion at NYU, and in 1843, he took on additional teaching duties in political economy. He also served as rector of the University Grammar School. Mason resigned from the University in January 1850. He died of typhoid fever on May 29, 1865, in New York City.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains correspondence of Cyrus Mason, dating from 1843 and mainly concerning finances and personal matters. Topics include religious life, the birth of a daughter to Susan Hilleron, a subscription fund for Union College, and the debts of Mason's brother, James.
Access Restrictions
Materials are open without restrictions.
Arrangement
Arranged in original order.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Found in repository.
Correspondence.; Religion.; University of the City of New York
- Barney, Hiram, 1843 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Bisher, J., 1843 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Brown, Mortimor, 1843 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Brown, Sarah, 1843 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Cushing, Thomas P., 1843 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Cook, R.S., 1843 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Donan, P., 1843 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Hilleron, C., 1843 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Mackey, James R., 1843 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Marton, A., 1843 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Mason, James, 1843 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Masters, A., 1843 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Norris, A., 1843 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Thorne, R., 1843 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Waterbury, Silvester, 1843 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Wilkinson, A., 1843-10 (Box 1, Folder 16)